Guide to the Maurice Hindus papers M2002
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
- Book reviews and correspondence, 1926-1968
  - Moscow Skies, 1936-1937
    - Promotional Poster, review of Under Moscow Skies, no year October 6 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - L.M.W., South Carolina, review of Moscow Skies, 1936 September 26 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Promotional Review,New York Times,Moscow Skies, 1936 September 27 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Dorothy Canfield,New York Herald, review of Moscow Skies, 1936 September 27 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Maurice L. Richardson, review of Moscow Skies, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Political Quarterly, review of Moscow Skies, 1937 April-June (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Sons and Fathers, 1937-1940
    - 2 TLS, Russell ? to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Sons and Fathers, 1937 September 16, 1937 October 4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - TLS, Victor Gollancz to Hindus, London; TL, Hindus to Gollancz, New York, New York, regarding new book-Sons and Fathers, 1937 October 14, 1937 October 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - TLS, Victor Gollancz to Hindus, London; TL Hindus to Gollancz, New York, New York, regarding new book-Sons and Fathers, 1937 October 16, 1937 October 29 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - TLS, Victor Gollancz to Hindus, London, regarding new novel-Sons and Fathers, 1937 September 24 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - TLS, Victor Gollancz to Hindus, London, regarding Sons and Fathers, 1937 September 14 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Promotional Review-Sons and Fathers, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Retail Bookseller, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Retail Bookseller, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Publisher's Weekly, New Jersey, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 3 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Evening Public Ledger, Philadelphia, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 3 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Hilton R. Coveer, Dallas, Texas, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 3 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Standard Times, Massachusetts, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 4 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Olga Owens, Boston, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 6 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Harry Hansen, Massachusetts, review of Sons and Fathers; Harry Hansen, Virginia, review of Sons and Fathers; Harry Hansen, Pennsylvania, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 6, 1940 February 8, 1940 February 13 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Press, Cleveland, Ohio, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 8 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Gazette Daily, Pennsylvania, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 9 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Time, Connecticut, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 9 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - News, Indianapolis, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Journal Courier, Indiana, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Nonpareil, Iowa, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Courier, California, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Call Bulletin, California, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - News, Indiana, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Journal, Pennsylvania, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - News, Cleveland, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - M.M., Connecticut, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 10 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Times, Ohio, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - M.G., North Carolina, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Star, Indiana, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Blade, Toledo, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Frank P. Gill, Michigan, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Vindicator, Ohio, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Plain Dealer, Ohio, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Morning Globe, Massachusetts, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - M.B., Texas, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Item, Louisiana, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - C.V. Roberts, Ohio, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - John Hutchinson, Memphis, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 11 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - R.J.L., Albany, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 12 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Reporter, New York, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 13 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - A.K., Philadelphia, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 14 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - H.S.A., Albany, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 14 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - James Gray, Minnesota, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 15 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Morning Star-Telegram, Texas, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 18 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Mail, Catskill, New York, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 February 20 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Observer Dispatch, Utica, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 March 10 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Star, Delaware, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 March 10 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Iola Fuller, New York, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 March 11 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Bulletin, Philadelphia, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 March 23 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - News, Louisiana, review of Sons and Fathers, 1940 March 24 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Green Worlds, 1938-1962
    - Blurb from Catalogue, review of Green Worlds, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - TLS, Frances Sweeney to Hindus, Massachusetts, regarding Green Worlds, 1938 August 22 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - TLS, Malcolm Johnson to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Green Worlds, 1938 December 8 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - TLS, Malcolm Johnson to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Green Worlds, 1938 November 7 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - TLS, Ken McCormick to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding reprint Green Worlds, 1947 March 28 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - TL, Hindus to Johnson, New York City, regarding Green Worlds, 1940 March 23 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - TLS, Victor Gollancz to Hindus, London; TL, Hindus to Gollancz, regarding Green Worlds, 1938 April 29, 1938 April 22 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - TLS, Victor Gollancz to Hindus, London, regarding Green Worlds, 1938 June 20 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - TLS, Anne Williams to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Green Worlds, 1939 March 30 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - TL, Hindus to Ethel R. Zimmer, Dallas, Texas, regarding Green Worlds, 1939 March 7 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - TLS, Joey R. Grunn to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding rights to Green Worlds, 1962 May 8 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Ola Cook,Times, review of Green Worlds, 1940 February 1 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - We Shall Live Again, 1939-1940
    - TL, Hindus to Bohus Benesh, New York City, regarding We Shall Live Again, 1939 April 26 (Box 8, Folder 1, Box 7)
    - TL, Hindus to Editor of "The Spectator," New York City, regarding review by Elizabeth Wiskenmann,We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 28 (Box 8, Folder 2, Box 7)
    - TL, Hindus to Patricia Fitzsimmons, Dallas, Texas, regarding We Shall Live Again, 1939 March 7 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Josephs Starobin, review of We Shall Live Again, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Will Durant, review of We Shall Live Again, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The New Yorker, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Philip Jordan, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Lewis Gannett, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Roy Fenton,Tribune, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 February 6 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Cleveland Democrat, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 April 23 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Daily Express, London, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 11 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - John Cournos,New York Sun, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Charles Poore,New York Times, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Charles Poore,New York Times, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Public Opinion, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - May Cameron,New York Post, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - May Cameron,New York Post, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Harry Hansen,New York World Telegram, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - The Times, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 12, 1939 May 17 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Henry C. Wolfe, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - The Times, London, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - The Times Literary Supplement, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Vincent L. Sheean, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 14 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Middletown News Journal, Ohio, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 14 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - George N. Shuster,New York Times, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 14 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Irish Independent, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 May 23 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 Late May (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Elizabeth Wiskemann, London, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - G.M. Little,Glasgow Bulletin, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Roy Fenton,The Tribune, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - L.A. Mackay, Toronto, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 3 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Edmund W. Peters, New York, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Lexington Herald Leader, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Durham Herald Sun, North Carolina, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - W.H.C.,Manchester Guardian, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 6 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Boston Post, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 6 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - New Orleans State, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 7 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Diogenes,Free Press, Winnipeg, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Toronto Globe and Mail, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Kansas City Star, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Spencer D. Irwin,Plain Dealer, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 11 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Buffalo Courier Express, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 11 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - S.L.A. Marshall,Detroit News, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 11 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Books of Today, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 12 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Georgiana G. Stevens,San Francisco Chronicle, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 12 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Garden News, Massachusetts, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 12 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - John Selby, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 4-12 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - T.M., South Africa, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 16 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Sunday Times, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 18 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Joseph A. Loewinsohn,The Atlantic Constitution, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 19 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Ralph Bates,New Republic, review of We Shall Live Again, 1939 June 21 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - News, Minnesota, review of We Shall Live Again, 1940 February 2 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Times, Indiana, review of We Shall Live Again, 1940 February 11 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - "American Library Association," Chicago, review of We Shall Live Again, 1940 February 15 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Lecture correspondence, Town Meeting of the Air, Radio/TV correspondence, Introductions/Recommendations, Non-Hindus correspondence, 1925-1962
  - Hindus-The Fate of Yekim, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hindus, Autobiographical Incomplete (Ch. II), pages 16-22, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hindus, Autobiographical Incomplete pages 1-12a, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hindus, Autobiographical Chapter pages 1-24, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hindus, Autobiographical Segment (pages 23-33), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hindus, "Chapter VI - The New Siberia", undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hindus, "the Appeaser," "The Trapper Trapped", undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - TL, Hindus to Wilma Haynes, Dallas, Texas, regarding lecture at Columbia, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - TLS, Vic Bernstein to Hindus, Berlin, regarding lecturing, 1938 December 29 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - TL, Hindus to Smilo, regarding lecture, 1940 January 20 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Town Meeting of the Air, 1941 February 10 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Bulletin of America's Town Meeting of the Air", 1939 December 4 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - TLS, Edward R. Murrow to Hindus, US Information Agency, regarding Russia Broadcast, 1962 April 24 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - TC, Mabel Hazlett Keep to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding recorded conversation, 1940 July 25 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - TLS, Ada Siegel to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding apology, 1951 May 8 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - TLS, Altoro L. Hall to Hindus, California, regarding town meeting, 1951 May 9 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - ALS, Flora I. Copple to Hindus, Olympia, Washington, regarding Town Meeting of the Air, 1939 December 1 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - TL, Hindus to Mr. Loomis, regarding Russian Broadcast, 1962 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - TLS, Henry Loomis to Hindus, Washington, regarding Russian broadcast, 1962 May 8 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - TLS, Spencer Williams to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding radio broadcast, 1961 September 22 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - TL, Hindus to George Field; TLS, George Field to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding Freedom House television series, 1951 April 10, 1951 March 29 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - TLS, William S. Paley to Hindus, New York, regarding Resolution-broadcasting, 1938 October 11 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - TLS, William Winter to Hindus, Charlotte, North Carolina, regarding photo-radio interview, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - TL, Hindus to Nikita S. Khrushchev, regarding visa request, 1958 April 22 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - TLS, Wendell I. Wilkie to Premier Joseph Stalin, New York, New York, regarding recommendation, 1943 August 3 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - TLS, John N. Wheeler to whom it may concern, New York, New York, regarding correspondent, 1941 July 17 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - TLS, R.B. Shipley to Hindus, Washington, regarding passport, 1941 August 12 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Speech Announcements, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Brackett Lewis to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding lecture, 1940 March 23 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - TLS, Mabel Hazlett to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding lecture, 1940 July 26 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - TLS, Walter Ricks to Hindus, Portland, Oregon, regarding lecture tour, 1925 November 24 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Walter Ricks to Hindus, Portland, Oregon, regarding lecture, 1925 November 30-December 17 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - TLS, W. Horsley Gantt to Hindus, Maryland, regarding lecture, 1938 October 28 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - TL, Hindus to Horsely Gante, Dallas, Texas, regarding lecture, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - TL, Hindus to Rabbi L.I. Newman, Dallas, Texas, regarding lecture program, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Helen D. Chase to Hindus, Buffalo, New York, regarding reaction to lecture, 1940 February 12 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Bill Colston Leigh to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding lecture, 1949 December 8 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - TLS, Elizabeth McClave to Hindus, San Francisco, California, regarding lecture, 1959 May 15 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - TL, Hindus to Dr. James Madison Wood, Dallas, Texas, regarding lecture, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - TLS, Henry I. Stahr to Hindus, Hood College, Fredrick, Maryland, regarding lecture at Hood College, 1947 March 19 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - TLS, Gertrude to Hindus, Massachusetts; TC, Elbert A. Wickes to S.R. Bridges, Massachusetts, regarding lecture, 1938 November 8 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - TLS, Monica to Hindus, Massachusetts, regarding lecture, 1939 January 31 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - TL, Hindus to Gertrude Lamothe, Dallas, Texas, regarding lecture, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - TL, Hindus to Frances Callaye, Dallas, Texas, regarding lecture, 1939 March 7 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - TLS, Kenneth Leslie to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding speech request, 1942 January 5 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - TLS, R.E. Barnette to Hindus, Cleveland Ohio, regarding transportation and photograph, 1925 November 23 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - TLS, Harold R. Peat to American Consul in London, New York, New York, regarding lectures, 1940 November 22 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - TLS, Russell Bridges to Hindus, Atlanta, Georgia, regarding lecture dates, 1938 June 21 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - TLS, Affiliated Association, INC. to Hindus, Cleveland, Ohio, regarding lecture membership, 1929 November 29 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - TLS, Walter H. Brown to Hindus, St. Louis, Missouri, regarding Brown Lyceum Bureau, 1927 December 9 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - TLS, Lambert Grant to Hindus, Utica, New York, regarding lecture, 1951 March 23 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - TL(2), American Broadcasting Company, INC. to Hindus, New York, New York, regarding town meeting of the air, 1951 May 8 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - TLS, Frank Bares, Sr. to Radio Station, WJR, Oxford, Michigan, regarding radio address Czech, 1938 April 3 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - TLS, Josef Hanc to Edith M. Yurka, New York, New York regarding introduction, 1938 June 9 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - TLS, Josef Hanc to Dr. Jaroslav Kraus, New York, New York regarding introduction, 1938 May 6 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - TLS, Josef Hanc to Dr. Karel Capek, New York, New York regarding introduction, 1938 May 6 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - TLS, John Rothschild to Antonin Palecek, New York, New York, regarding introduction, 1938 May 2 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - TL, Hindus to Boris E. Skvirsky, Jamestown, TN, regarding Visa & interview with Stalin, 1928 April 27 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - TLS(2), William E. Borah to Hindus, U.S. Senate, regarding recommendation, 1938 June 16 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - TL, Hindus to Leonid Ilyichev, regarding Visa request, 1958 April 22 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - TL, Hindus to Yirii Zhukov, regarding Visa request, 1958 April 22 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - ALS, Norton A. Green to George Green, Cassville, New York, regarding Hindus, 1938 August 17 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - TLS (3), Raymond Robins to Oswald Ryan, Florida, regarding Franklyn Ward, 1938 September 13, 24, and October 1 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - TL, Ralph T. Fisher, Jr., to Helen M. Welch, Connecticut, regarding meeting with Hindus, 1959 June 27 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - ALS, Lee to Ernestine Evans, New York, regarding personal, 1940 July 16 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - TL, Frank Goldschmied to Sirs, Prague, regarding Air Raid Precautions office, 1938 November 11 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - TLS, Elisha Zack to Joe Freeman, Brooklyn, New York, regarding personal, 1940 August 21 (Box 9, Folder 67)
- Articles, short manuscripts, interviews, and speeches, 1925-1968
  - Yugoslavia relations, 1961, undated
    - Hindus, "Aid to Yugoslavia Backed", New York - YUG #2, 1961 October 17 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Hindus on Yugoslav/Russian Relations - YUG #1, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Peace, 1942-1950
    - Hindus, "No Peaceful Revolution", New York - PEACE #2, 1950 August 8 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hindus, "What Are We Fighting For?" - PEACE #3, 1942 April 29 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hindus, "Belgrade and Moscow" - PEACE #1, undated; 3 pages (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - People, 1929-1952
    - Hindus, "Lady Astor" - PEOPLE A, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Hindus, Write-Up of Louis Fischer for Jewish Encyclopedia - PEOPLE F, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hindus, "A Talk with Gordienko" - PEOPLE G, 1939 June (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hindus "Jews" - PEOPLE J, undated; 8 pages (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Hindus, "Russian Jewry Under Collective Farming" - PEOPLE J, 1930 June (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Hindus on Litvinov's death - PEOPLE L, 1952 January 13 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Hindus, "Litvinov" - PEOPLE L, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Hindus on Georgi Malenkov - PEOPLE M, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Hindus on Shah Mohamed Rea Pahlevi - PEOPLE P, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - TC, Hindus, "Too Late for Calumny - An Open Letter to Konstantin Simonov". The Saturday Review of Literature - PEOPLE S, 1951 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Hindus on Churchill Speech - PEOPLE C, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Hindus, "Bookless Philosophers" - PEOPLE D, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Hindus, "Gordienko, Russia, and the War" - PEOPLE G, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Hindus, "Why Didn't You Come" - Gorki - PEOPLE G, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Hindus Response to Professor Elsworth Huntington - PEOPLE H, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Hindus on Peter Kapitsa - PEOPLE K, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Hindus "Lenin the Russian" - PEOPLE L, undated; 17 pages (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Hindus Original, "Too Late for Calumny" - PEOPLE S, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Hindus on Rudolf Slansley - PEOPLE S, undated; 8 pages (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Hindus, "Marshall of the Soviet Union, Semyon Timoshenko" - PEOPLE T, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Hindus, "The Fall of Trotzky" - PEOPLE T, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Hindus on Truman's Inaugural Address - PEOPLE T, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Hindus on Mao-Tse-Tung - PEOPLE T, 1949; 10 pages (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Hindus on Weizman Institute of Science - PEOPLE W, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Cold War, 1932, undated
    - Hindus, "What Shall We Do With Russia" - COLD WAR #1, 1932; 17 pages (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Hindus, "Stalin wants/needs a Truce or Cold War" - COLD WAR #2, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Hindus on Moscow - Belgrade Cold War - COLD WAR #3, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Korean War, undated
    - Hindus - Kremlin Affairs/Korean War - KOR #1, undated; 8 pages (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Russian/German relations, undated
    - Hindus - Discussion of Russian/German Relations - RUS/GER #1, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Hindus, "The Coming War Between Russia & Germany" - RUS/GER #2, undated; 33 pages (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Hindus, "Coming War Between Russia and Germany" - RUS/GER #3, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Hindus, "At Daggers' Ends" - RUS/GER #4, undated; 7 pages (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Hindus, "At Daggers' Ends" - RUS/GER #5, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Hindus, "Russia is Stronger than Hitler Suspected" - RUS/GER #6, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Egypt, undated
    - Hindus, Egypt - Short manuscript. EGYPT #1, undated; 8 pages (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Finland, 1939, undated
    - Hindus, "Helsinki" - FINLAND #1, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Hindus, "Sons of Kallevala" - FINLAND #2, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Persia, undated, 1948
    - Hindus, "Persian Power in a Saddle" The Star Weekly. Toronto - PERSIA #2, 1948 January 10 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Hindus on Persia - PERSIA #1, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Hindus, "Firuzabad, Persia" - PERSIA #2, no year October 11, no year October 26 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Hindus, "Isphahan" - PERSIA #3, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Hindus, "Kherak" - PERSIA #4, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)